Today we're going to do frozen yogurt or
yogurt if that's how you pronounce it.
Loads of people have asked for it. I
would never buy this in the store. I
don't know why. I I eat yogurt most days
to be fair. Usually this stuff. But when
you make frozen yogurt at home, the the
breakdown of it ingredients wise, it's
kind of like gelato. It it's the similar
numbers, but it's higher in milk solids,
nonfat. So that kind of means skimm milk
powder, milk proteins, that kind of
thing. That's how it
is made. Now, when you go to the store,
there are a million different types of
yogurt available. Um, this is the kind
of one that I eat here. Uh, this is the
black cherry with chocolate pieces. But
the the important part is the the little
symbol at the top that tells you how
much milk fat is in here. So, this is
2%. If you use zero% milk fat, 1 2 3%
milk fat yogurt to make this, it it's
really difficult to get it balanced
right. So, I suggest you go and get
something like this, which is 5% milk
fat. And just makes life so much easier
and the result is perfect. So, what are
we going to need to make our frozen
yogurt? You are going to need 215 g of
milk at 3.5% so whole milk. 474 g of our
5% milk fat yogurt. This is Greek
yogurt. And I recommend you do the same.
85 g of whipping cream. So any cream
that's 33% or higher. 138 g of sugar. 17
g of invert sugar, which is corn syrup
or glucose. 5 g of vanilla extract. 3 g
of our stabilizer and finally 60 g of
skim milk powder. The skim milk powder
is high in this recipe, like I said,
because it's got higher milk solids,
non-fat. The invert sugar, glucose
syrup, you can buy in any supermarket in
the baking aisle all around the world.
Don't have to stress about that one at
all. Corn syrup is absolutely fine. You
can use golden syrup, too. No worries
whatsoever. just it it's to change that
texture. It's to bring the texture that
can quite often be a little bit grainy
and icy with frozen yogurt and bring it
back into the luxury mouth feel that
we're used to here on this channel. So,
let's get everything weighed out and
ready. Right, let's start with our milk.
215 g. In with our yogurt with this one,
474 g. Into that goes our cream, 85 g.
Cream is quite important. Into that goes
our sugar, 138 g. I'm going to put
in 30 g. Into a small little container
cuz I'm using a stabilizer. I'm putting
the
remaining
teaspoon. And I'm going to use my
442 blend stabilizer. In that goes. I'm
using my 442 blend. Use whatever
stabilizer you have. Into there. We're
going to put in our invert sugar. We're
just going to use corn syrup. And this
is 17 g. We're going to put in our milk
powder. 60 g. So, with everything in our
pan, we're going to just get this
stirred together. Well, that yogurt in
there is going to make a mess, so just
go slow. Let's get this on the hob. This
stabilizer needs heating. So, we're
going to heat this up to 85 C, 185 F. If
you use a cold processed stabilizer,
just heat it up enough to bring all the
ingredients together. That's usually
around the 50° centigrade mark. Anyway,
let's get this on the hob. Right, we're
up to temperature. Going to give that
just five minutes just to cool down a
bit. It's going to thicken. This base is
going to get thick. All right, so don't
stress about that. That's just what it's
going to do. Now it's cooled down just
for a few minutes. We're going to put
our vanilla extract in. You can put
between 5 and 10 g of vanilla extract in
here. The recipe, because the way yogurt
works, will take it absolutely no
problems whatsoever. So now that that's
mixed in, smells
delicious. There we are simply going to
get this into a container. It's likely
going to look like it's separating in
the fridge. Don't worry about it. It's
very normal for frozen yogurt. So in the
fridge it goes for 3 to 4 hours to
completely chill down. Right. So with
our frozen yogurt base chilling in the
fridge, we're going to do a couple of
add-ins. Now I'm going to do a cherry
chocolate frozen yogurt. And that's
because that's the flavor yogurt that I
eat. Um, so I'm going to use this. Uh,
you've seen this on the channel before.
I find Fabri syrups to be the best
available, hands down. There is no
comparison. Um, there's lots of
different syrups available. There are
some that are shockingly bad, but I'm
actually going to show you how to
make I'm actually going to show you how
to make these cuz they're basically just
flavored sugar water. Um, and some of
these like $30, $40 a bottle and you can
make it for about three. With that in
mind, we're going to make a cherry
syrup. This is pretty decent as it is.
It's just a bit thin. So, what we need
to do is get some of this in here.
Weight is kind of irrelevant. Use as
much as you need to use, but I'm going
to put in
approximately 100 g of that cherry syrup
in there. And we're going to need to add
something to thicken it up. Um, that
something is going to be a cold process
stabilizer and it's going to
be not that
one. Zantham gum cherries super acidic.
Um, some stabilizers just don't like
acidic environments. So, we're going
with zantham gum, which is absolutely
fine. We're going to take a scant
teaspoon of sugar, a half teaspoon. So
you know 2 and 1 half 3 g of zantham gum
and just swirl that together break up
any lumps and distribute that stabilizer
within that sugar. Now you are simply
going to add that to there and stir it
all together. If for some reason it
clumps up, you can just pop this in a
mini blender or something and process
that. You can also heat it up in a
microwave just for 5 or 10 seconds. Um
that's a really good way to deal with
sugars and clumping for some
ingredients. So, let's There we go. 10
seconds in the microwave. I'm going to
get a mini whisk just to make life
easier
and whisk it together. If for some
reason you really struggle there, some
some syrups really struggle to dissolve
additional solids like stabilizers and
and the such in it. You can literally
put it on a hob in a pan, a small pan,
and just heat it up, whisk it, and then
eventually it will break down those
clumps that are left. So, learning how
your ingredients are best processed is
key to any recipe really. Right, we
we're completely dissolved there. Let's
get a lid for that. And that is going to
go in the fridge. That's it for now.
Once the frozen yogurt's come down to
temperature, we'll bring it out and
we'll churn it. This recipe is great in
a Ninja Creamy or the icy treat kind of
style machine uh because frozen yogurt
will thicken up in the refrigerator. But
today's video, we're going to do it in a
churn machine. So, I'll see you in a
bit. So, now that our frozen yogurt base
is completely ched, I'm going to take it
out of the fridge and we're going to
whisk it. As you can see, it is pretty
thick. So, we do need to stir this back
together before we can actually add it
to our
machine. Pouring in. We're going to
churn this as normal. It won't take as
long. We won't get quite as much overrun
as we would do with an ice cream or a
gelato because of the high solids
content. But anyway, in that goes, we're
going to get that spinning because now
we are going to deal with our chocolate.
This is a 70% dark chocolate. This
happens to be Calibo chocolate, but use
any 70% chocolate you like. I'm grating
some and then I'm slicing some others. I
want some smaller pieces and some larger
pieces in here. So, with that said and
done, out comes our cherry syrup. This
is super thick now. As you can see, all
the powder is completely dissolved. And
towards the end of the churn, we're
going to start adding in our chocolate.
Make sure that's completely
incorporated. And load up our
containers. A scoop full of our frozen
yogurt and one small spoon of our cherry
syrup. And just keep going until you
load everything up. And then put it in
the freezer to completely harden off for
about 3 to 4 hours. After that time, we
can take it out the freezer and have a
look. See what Oh, it looks incredible.
This is a chocolate cherry swirl. Lovely
smell of yogurt. Let's get some served
up. And look at that beautiful cherry
swirl. Lovely large and small flexcks of
chocolate. This looks and smells
delicious. Cherry and Duck chocolate
frozen yogurt. This is, you know, kind
of black foresty kind of flavors.
Beautiful texture. It's very kind of
similar to ice cream texture, but a
little bit different. The biggest
difference comes from that
acidic tang from the from the yogurt.
Greek yogurt. Impeccable
flavors. Super super good. I mean really
good. I mean really good. Again, just a
touch. This is This is the yogurt that
I'm kind of imitating. I'll put a bigger
picture here. Uh it's 2% milk fat, but
this is a black cherry chocolate pieces
stretchella collection
liberte. It's my favorite flavor. I
mean, this is so so good. Give it a try.
If you've never made frozen yogurt
before, it this is the one to to get you
going. This is the one to start that
journey. It's incredibly good. Recipe in
the description below. Thanks very much
for all my supporters on YouTube and
Patreon. If you want to join Patreon or
support me on YouTube, the links are in
the description. Please don't forget to
like this video and subscribe to the
channel. It really helps the algorithm
help grow this ice cream making family.
Anyway, thanks very much for watching.
Don't forget to like and subscribe
again. I will see you next week.
[Music]